# **Dexter Carpenter**

Mechanical Engineering Major 503-964-9532 | dextercarpenter1@gmail.com | github.com/DexterCarpenter

# **Overview**

I'm a fifth-year engineering student at OSU looking for work over the Summer. I have experience working in the food industry for several years. I am familiar with handling food and the physical requirements needed to be effective. I have also previously worked at a lab at OSU where inventory and asset management was important, such I am familiar with keeping an environment orderly and organized. Being an aspiring engineer, I am very meticulous and methodical with what I do, with a good attention to detail and critical thinking. From working in the service industry, I am familiar with working with customers and how to properly help them.

# **Work Experience**

Pinolo Gelato, Gelateria, 2016-2017

- Gelato server, cashier, barista
  - Served Gelato, kept stock of cups/spoons/gelato, check out customers, take orders, clean shop, etc.

Xico, Oaxacan Restaurant, 2016-2019

- Initially helped occasionally with food prep jobs
- Became part-time dishwasher over the summer and throughout school year
- Became part-time busser/FOH staff
  - Cleaned tables, delivered food, kept stock of dishes, napkins, utensils, etc.

#### OPEnS Lab Project Lead (Oregon State) Jan 2021 – Nov 2022

Project Lead for 'FloDar' Project

#### **Educator**

- Math & Science tutor for High School Equivalency Program at OSU, Sept 2020 Jan 2021
- Private math tutor, Summer 2020 2022
- FIRST LEGO League Mentoring, 2019

# **Education**

### Oregon State University, Corvallis Campus – GPA: 2.76

- Mechanical Engineering Degree, Minor in Mathematics
- 5<sup>th</sup> year student

# **Portland Community College** – GPA: 3.75

• Took a few math courses, and a machine shop class

#### Cleveland High School, Portland OR - GPA: 3.725

Graduation Date: June 2019

- Honors and Awards
  - Recipient of IB Thinker Award 2015/2016 School Year

#### References

Ben Leshchinsky, Associate Professor, Stakeholder, <u>ben.leshchinsky@oregonstate.edu</u> Chet Udell, Assistant Professor, OPEnS Lab Manager, <u>udellc@oregonstate.edu</u>